开萝尔:今晚我很开心,博比.
Carol: I had a great time tonight Bobby.
博比:耶,我也很开心.跟你在一起,什么我都喜欢.
Bobby: Yeah.Me too.I could like anything if I went with you.
开萝尔:甚至芭蕾?
Carol: Even the ballet?
博比:对.怎么提这碴儿,你有票?
Bobby: Sure.Why, you got tickets?
开萝尔:没.
Carol: No.
博比:呣----
Bobby: Ummm.
开萝尔:有事?
Carol: Yes?
博比:我想问,你是否愿意……
Bobby: I was gonna ask if you wanted ..
开萝尔:我会很高兴去.
Carol: I would love to go.
博比:去哪儿?
Bobby: Go where.
开萝尔:不管你要请我去哪儿.
Carol: Well, wherever you were going to suggest we should go.
博比:我要问的是你是否愿意今晚和我一块学习.
Bobby: I was going to ask if you wanted to study together tomorrow night.
开萝尔:哦,没问题.
Carol: Oh sure.
博比:我……
Bobby: Well..
开萝尔:呃?天哪,难道这学年过得还不快么,
Carol: Uh hu?Boy isn't this school year just flying by?
跟飞似的?我,我的意思是说时间过得好快哦,
I mean well, first it was summer and then it was fall and pretty soon
最开始是夏天,然后秋天,转眼就要到杜威高中冬季舞会的时间了.
it will be time for the Dewey High Winter dance.
博比:对啊,马上就要到冬季舞会了.我我……我得走了.晚安,开萝尔.
Bobby: Yeah, the winter dance.I I...I got to go.Good night Carol.
迈克:嗨,博比.
Mike: Hey Bobby
博比:嗨,马克(注:伙伴对迈克的称呼,显得更为亲密).
Bobby: Hey Mark.
迈克:我叫迈克.
Mike: Mike.
开萝尔:真巧啊,迈克.
Carol: Nice timing Mike.
迈克:那就是我妹妹,挺傲的,别搭理她.
Mike: That was just my surly sister.Don't mind her.
(接吻)
(kiss)
迈克:喂,你好,安德里亚.谢谢你今天送我回家,我的车在修理厂呢.
Mike: Well hello Andrea.I just want to thank you for driving me home today while my car was in the shop.
安德里亚:非常荣幸.
Andrea: My pleasure.
迈克:来啊,好像我欠了你一两个吻似的;你不就是掏了点小钱么,汽油,电影还有吃的.
Mike: Well hold on man.Come on, you act like I owe you a kiss
or two just because you paid for the gas and the movie and the food
安德里亚:你不想吻我么?
Andrea: You don't want to kiss me?
迈克:当然了,我太想吻你了.只不过,
Mike: Of course I want to kiss you.
我还得考虑考虑我的名声问题.好了,我想好了.
It's just that, well I got my reputation to think about.Ok, I'm done thinking.
朋友1:那,博比昨晚请你去这次舞会了么?
Friend 1: So, did bobby ask you to the dance last night?
开萝尔:还没明确说.
Carol: well not exactly.
朋友2:还没?
Friend 2: No?
开萝尔:是的,还没.
Carol: No?
朋友2:换了我,我会死的.
Friend 2: I could die.
朋友1:他总得提一提冬季舞会什么的吧?
Friend 1: Did he even mention the winter formal?
开萝尔:啊,没提.
Carol: uh no
朋友1:没提?
Friend 1: No?
开萝尔:是我提的.
Carol: I brought up the winter dance.
朋友2:你不会吧?
Friend 2: You didn't?
开萝尔:对,就是我提的.
Carol: I did.
朋友2:换了我,我会死的.
Friend 2: I could die.
朋友1:开萝尔,这可不好.
Friend 1: Carol, this is not a good thing.
开萝尔:为什么呢?
Carol: Why?
朋友2:为什么?!
Friend 2: Why?
朋友1:男人不喜欢越俎代庖的女人.
Friend 1: Men don't like women who usurp their masculinity
开萝尔:我没有越俎代庖,好了吧?
Carol: I didn't ucirc ok?
朋友1:开萝尔,你刚才去哪儿了?让男人管事儿的女人,男人才喜欢,即使那样你会表现的有些傻傻的样子.
Friend 1: Carol, where have you been?Men like women who let them be in charge, even if that means you have to act dumb.
朋友2:我已经有充分的思想准备了.
Friend 2: Which I'm fully prepared to do.
开萝尔:听着!我可没有邀请博比参加冬季舞会,我只是,给他点儿暗示.
Carol: Look!I didn't ask Bobby to the winter formal.I just, sort of hinted.
朋友1:开萝尔,踢足球的才不会带自己的家庭女老师去跳舞呢.他们要请的是,金发女郎,穿着带褶儿的短裙,能把他们的身体蹂躏得体无完肤的人.
Friend 1: Carol, football players do not take their tutors to the prom.They take blonde girls in pleated skirts who can turn their bodies into letters of the alphabet.
博比:喂,圣诞快乐.
Bobby: Alright Chris.
开萝尔: 别回头,好吧?
Carol: Don't turn around.Ok?
朋友们:(尖叫)他冲这边过来了.
Friends: (Squealing) He's coming this way.
开萝尔:谢谢你雪莉.
Carol: Thanks Shelly.
朋友1:跑掉吧.
Friend 1: Run away.
开萝尔:好了,不要神经病了.如果你们现在跑,
Carol: Now don't be ridiculous.
他就会知道我们正在聊他.所以呢,
If you run away from here, he'll know that we're talking about him.
就这么慢慢地走开,而且要非常非常地镇静.明白了?
So just walk away, very cool, and very very calmly.Ok.
朋友们:(尖叫)
Friends: (squealing)
博比:嗨.
Bobby: Hi
开萝尔:嗨.
Carol: Hi
博比:明天晚上一块学习,怎么样?
Bobby: About studying together tomorrow night.
开萝尔:啊,五点钟是不是太早了一点?
Carol: Ah is five too early?
博比:不早,太晚了我不行.
Bobby: No.I can't make it.
开萝尔:你不行?
Carol: You can't?
博比:不不.有件事,
Bobby: No, no.Something came up.
不过我想在电话里跟你说.
But I'd like to call you and talk to you about it.
我的意思是说,你看你们这会儿不是正往家赶么.
I mean, well, if you're going to be at home.
开萝尔:我可能那时在家,那打电话,打电话.
Carol: I might be.Ring.Ring.
本:嗨!
Ben: Hi!
开萝尔:把电话拿起来,就不用手举那么高了.
Carol: Shhhh!Pick up that phone and you'll never use that hand again.
本:哦,高谈阔论!
Ben: Oh big talk!
迈克:嗨,萨曼塔,谢谢你今天送我回家.
Mike: Hey Samantha.Thanks for the ride home today.
萨曼塔:非常荣幸.
Samantha: My pleasure.
迈克:你还得再等我一小时,直到我从集中营出来,
Mike: Oh and uh,
谢谢等我.
thanks for waiting that extra hour till I got out of detention.
萨曼塔:哦,你的书,别忘了.
Samantha: Oh here are your books.
迈克:谢谢.待会儿见.
Mike: Thanks.Bye
萨曼塔:待会儿见.
Samantha: Bye.
迈克:哦,我太喜欢每年这个时候了,
Mike: Oh, I love this time of year.Right before the winter formal.
刚好快到冬季舞会了.女孩们都如此的迫不及待.
Girls get so desperate.
开萝尔:你这头猪.
Carol: You're a pig.
迈克:谢谢.
Mike: Thank you.
开萝尔:本,如果你修不好那电话,那赶紧走吧.
Carol: Ben, if you can't make the phone ring, leave.
本:没问题.
Ben: Ok.
开萝尔:我也没问题.
Carol: Ok.
(电话响起)
(phone rings)
本:(尖叫)奇迹,我真是个大师.迈克,电话响了!
Ben: (scream) It's a miracle.I'm a total master with the power.Mike the phone is ringing!
迈克:那还不接.
Mike: so answer it.
开萝尔:别别别.拿起话机,然后非常镇静地说声"你好",之后再叫我,好像我在别的房间的样子.好么?
Carol: No no, no.Pick up the phone and very calmly say hello and call to me like I'm not in the room.Ok?
本:好的.你好,请稍等片刻.开萝尔!
Ben: Ok.Hello, just a minute.Carol!
开萝尔:来了.
Carol: Yes.
本:是找迈克的.
Ben: It's for mike.
迈克:什么?!
Mike: What.
本:是埃迪打的.
Ben: It's Eddie.
开萝尔:那就挂了它.
Carol: Well hang it up.
迈克:喂,开萝尔.
Mike: Look Carol.Carol come on.
开萝尔,别闹了.你总不能不是你的电话就挂吧.
You can't just hang up every phone call that's not for you.
本:我又做了一次.
Ben: I did it again.
迈克:你好.不,对不起.本死掉了.
Mike: Hello.No I'm sorry.Ben's dead.
本:嗨!干么呢你?
Ben: Hey!What are you doing?
迈克:给埃迪打过去.
Mike: Calling Eddie back.
开萝尔:不!
Carol: No!
迈克:打.
Mike: Yes.
开萝尔:不.
Carol: No
本:最后一次,我烦死了.
Ben: That's the last call.I'm bushed.
迈克:你好.嗨!我正在用电话呢.噢!噢!嗨,
Mike: Hello.Hey!I'm using the phone.Ow!Ow!Hey that hurt.
开萝尔:你好?哦,博比.你打过来挺是时候的么我刚好在,我刚才刚出了大门.
Carol: Hello?Oh hi Bobby.Lucky you caught me.I was just heading out the door.
麦琪:嗨,亲爱的.
Maggie: Hi honey.
杰森:嗨.
Jason: Hi.
麦琪和杰森:那,晚饭吃什么?
Maggie and Jason: So.What's for dinner?
麦琪和杰森:哦!
Maggie and Jason: Oh!
迈克:我觉得得告诉你们俩,你们的女儿刚刚又欺侮我了.
Mike: You know you guys should know that your daughter just brutalized me.
麦琪:真是我的闺女.
Maggie: That's my girl.
杰森:迈克,有个叫安德里亚的女孩打过电话来,
Jason: Mike, someone named Andrea called.She said winter is in the air.
说"冬天已经来了";还有一个叫萨曼塔的,"
Also Samantha called to quote; "formalize what she should bring you for
列出来明天午餐她应该给你带什么吃的";希娜打电话,说了声"嗨".
lunch tomorrow".And Sheena called to say "hey".
迈克:什么,什么,才三个人的留言?
Mike: What, what.Only three messages?
麦琪:迈克,你怎么能这样勾引这些女孩,很不公平的.
Maggie: Michael I think it's very unfair of you to lead these girls on.
迈克:勾引她们?妈妈,
Mike: Lead them on?Mum, look!
杜威高中里,
Fact, the enrollment at Dewy High is three to one female.
男女生三比一;还有啊,
Fact, the dance of the year is coming up.
今年的舞会马上就到了;还有啊,就鲍纳那样的还有女生给他打电话呢.
And fact, even Boner has women calling him.
杰森:天哪!
Jason: Good Lord!
开萝尔:别挡我道儿,小痞子.
Carol: Out of my way armpit.
迈克:看看,看看.我做了什么招惹人的事儿了,她那样恶毒地攻击我?
Mike: See.See?Did I do anything to provoke that vicious attack?
杰森:开萝尔,你这样不太好.迈克做错什么了么?
Jason: Carol, that wasn't very nice.What did Mike do?
迈克:没.
Mike: Nothing.
开萝尔:没做对过.
Carol: Nothing is right.
他就跟在地球上走过两步路的所有其它男的一样让人恶心.
He's just slime like every other male that ever walked the face of the earth.
杰森:那你自己处理这事儿吧,宝贝.
Jason: Maybe you better handle this honey.
麦琪:开萝尔,不要指所有男性.
Maggie: Carol.You don't mean all men.
开萝尔:不,我就.
Carol: Yes I do.
麦琪:那,对于你爸爸而言可不礼貌.
Maggie: Well, it's very insulting to your father.
开萝尔:我觉得爸爸不是男人.
Carol: I don't think of dad as a man.
杰森:这是件衬衫?
Jason: Is it the shirt?
开萝尔:你明白我的意思,我现在说的是非常帅气的男孩.
Carol: You know what I mean.I'm talking about hot good looking guys.
杰森:我闻到点味儿了.
Jason: I sense a trend here.
迈克:哦,我明白了.
Mike: Oh, I get it.
博比已经约了另外的女孩参加这次的"冬天里的一把火"了,是不是?
Bobby invited somebody else to this Winter Flame thing, huh?
开萝尔:男人都这样是吧,利用女人,
Carol: Typical of men who use women and then discard them like so much
然后扔了就跟扔垃圾似的.
garbage.
迈克:啊,那可真的很伤人哦,
Mike: Ah, that really hurts, Carol.
开萝尔.所以,
It hurts that you see me as a guy that treats girls very carnally.
你看到我这样的男人很功利地对待女孩,你就不舒服.
And if you'll excuse me,
不过,如果你能原谅我,
I have to go return some phone calls and brighten the day of some very
我可以过去回几个电话,让某些吉星高照的女士们眼前一亮.
lucky young ladies.
麦琪:那,你想不想给开萝尔讲讲男人,或者给迈克讲讲女人?
Maggie: So do you want to explain men to carol, or women to mike.
杰森:我还想让某些人给我讲讲女人呢.开个玩笑.
Jason: I'd like someone to explain women to me.Just kidding.
好了,迈克!
Just one of those charming whimsical remarks.Oh Mike!
麦琪:哦,开萝尔,我真替你难过,博比请了别的女孩.
Maggie: Oh carol, I'm so sorry that Bobby asked someone else.
开萝尔:我还不知道他已经请了别人,
Carol: I don't know that he asked someone else.
我不知道他心里是怎么想的.
I don't know what his plans are.
麦琪:宝贝,看出来了么,博比一直都有点害羞.
Maggie: Well, honey.You know that bobby's always been a little shy.
开萝尔:对,不过,他那天晚上不是那么很害羞,当时……无所谓.
Carol: Oh yeah, he wasn't so shy the other night, when...never mind.
麦琪:哪天晚上?
Maggie: What other night?
开萝尔:这不重要,重要的是再有一周零三天就举行舞会了,他还没有邀请我呢.
Carol: That's not the point.The point is that the dance is only a week
and a half away and he hasn't asked me yet
麦琪:那么,或许你应该邀请他啊.
Maggie: Well maybe you should ask him.
开萝尔:主动请男人跳舞的女人都是些风流成性的人.
Carol: The only kind of women who ask men to dances are the kind who don't
shave their legs.
麦琪:开萝尔,女人主动约男人出来,
Maggie: Carol, there is absolutely nothing wrong with a woman asking a
根本没什么不对啊.而且,极易成功.
man out on a date.It is extremely easy to do.
开萝尔:肯定的.
Carol: Oh sure.
麦琪:就是这样.看.怎么了,杰森?
Maggie: It's sure.Watch.Oh Jason?
杰森:对.
Jason: Yeah.
麦琪:周五晚上你想去看电影么?
Maggie: Would you like to go to the movies on Friday night?
杰森:想.
Jason: Sure.
麦琪:看什么?
Maggie: See.
杰森:你想看到什么?
Jason: What do you want to see?
麦琪:没什么,我们又不是真的要去看.我们周五已经有安排了.
Maggie: Oh, nothing.We're not really going.We already have plans on Friday.
杰森:哦!那我呢?
Jason: Oh!Where was I?
迈克:呣,你刚才告诉我说,
Mike: Um, you were telling me that I was wrong to think that women don't
我觉得女人不讲道理,这是错误的想法.
make sense.
朋友1:我刚才是说,听你母亲的建议有一个很大的误区.
Friend 1: I was just saying that it's a major mistake to follow your mothers' advice.
朋友2:对,如果按照你母亲所说,那我岂不是成了个教徒.
Friend 2: Yeah.If I followed my mothers' advice, I'd be a Quaker.
开萝尔:嗨,博比.
Carol: Hi Bobby.
博比:开萝尔.
Bobby: Carol.
开萝尔:是这样的,我们已经约会到现在差不多,有两个月?
Carol: Listen, we've been going out for what now, two months?
博比:对.
Bobby: Yeah
开萝尔:嗯,在这段时间里呢,我们已经成为非常要好的朋友.
Carol: Right.And in that time we've gotten to be really good friends.
博比:对.
Bobby: Yeah.
开萝尔:彼此相处的确是非常非常的开心,所以呢,我们没必要刻意遮掩什么.
Carol: So really comfortable around each other so we don't need to put up any kind of act.
博比:对.
Bobby: Yeah.
开萝尔:好极了.那,如果我要你请我参加今年的冬季舞会,你会……
Carol: Great.So, if I were going to ask you to take me to the winter formal, you'd say...
博比:不.
Bobby: No.
开萝尔:太好了!噢!
Carol: Great!Oh!
博比:我不能.
Bobby: I can't.
开萝尔:啊,那也没什么.我很高兴我们之间的事情澄清了.哦,
Carol: Well that's great.I'm glad we got that cleared up.
看看时间,我得走了.回见.
Oh gee look at the time.I got to go.Bye.
博比:开萝尔,我,我那会儿有球赛.
Bobby: Carol, I, it's my football.
杰森:遇到这样的活性很高的组合,比如草药和香料,一定要记住打开之前用力地摇动.
Jason: For that zesty combination of herbs and spices, always remember to shake vigorously before opening.Ok.
麦琪:你在做什么?
Maggie: What are you doing?
杰森:在烹饪.看起来如何啊?
Jason: I'm cooking.What does it look like?
麦琪:嗨,迈克.
Maggie: Hey Mike.
迈克:嗨,妈妈,还有您,爸爸.这次冬季舞会肯定是我的死期.
Mike: Hey mum.Yo dad.This winter formal thing is going to be the death
of me
杰森:呵.
Jason: Uh hum.
迈克:这么说吧,如果你必须做出选择,一个金发美女,
Mike: Ok, right if you had to choose between a blonde,
一个红发美女,还有一个小黑妹,你会选择哪个?
a redhead and a brunette beauty, who would you pick?
杰森:迈克,重要的是这个女人而不是她的头发,还有,她的头脑也很重要.
Jason: Well Mike, there's much more to a woman than the color of her hair.
嗨,开萝尔,你这一天怎么样?
There's also the size of her intellect.Hi Carol, how was your day?
开萝尔:一切都好.也不完全是了.
Carol: Everything's fine.Not really.
我自己也不知道最近我是怎么了,又是新衣服,
I don't know what's the matter with me lately, I mean new clothes, make up,
又是化妆品,隐形眼镜;一直想的都是某个人会请我去舞会.
contact lenses.Thinking someone would want to take me to a dance.Please!
让我说完!我是说,
I mean it's just not me.I mean what am I trying to change?
不只是我一个人.我这是要变成什么样子?
I was a fine just working hard and studying.
以前,只是努力学习我也过得很好啊;不争奇斗艳,
I was just fine without trying to be silly and popular.
不是取悦于他人,我也可以过得悠然自得.
I mean who needs all these risks?Well not me.
迈克:这就是说,她今天过得不顺利.
Mike: I guess this means she didn't have a good day.
开萝尔:妈妈,我想把我所有的化妆品捐赠给穷人们.
Carol: Mum, I want to donate all my make up to the poor.
麦琪:开萝尔,发生了什么事?
Maggie: Carol, what happened?
开萝尔:没事,没什么事啊.不就是我请博比去舞会然后他把拒绝了么.
Carol: Nothing.Nothings wrong.I just asked Bobby to the prom and he turned me down.
麦琪和杰森:哦,宝贝!
Maggie and Jason: Oh, honey!
杰森:好哇,真是羞辱.
Jason: Ok, that's a shame.
迈克:我还有主意要拿,先走了.我走到你前边了.
Mike: With the decision I've got to make, I don't need to see this.I'm way ahead of you.
麦琪:哦,宝贝,博比都说了些什么?
Maggie: Oh honey, what did Bobby say?
开萝尔:不.我得重复多少次啊?
Carol: No.How many times do I have to repeat it?
杰森:这样的,宝贝,可能是你请太请得太迟了.
Jason: Well honey, maybe you just asked him too late.
麦琪:肯定是有什么原因的.
Maggie: There has to be some reason.
开萝尔:是我,他不想接受的是我.
Carol: I'm me.I mean he just doesn't want to take me.
杰森:如果这样,他一定是昏了头了,这是我的看法,专家意见.
Jason: Well then he's out of his mind.And that's a professional opinion.
开萝尔:对,你说的没错.毕竟,我从痛苦中有所醒悟.如果你的智商达到了140,你还会需要什么社交生活.我说的没错吧?
Carol: Yes you're right, I mean, after all I've learned from my pain.I mean, who needs a social life when you've got an IQ of a hundred and forty four.Right?
麦琪:我想跟那个踢足球的开诚布公地谈谈,
Maggie: I want just five minutes with that football player without his
就五分钟.
protective equipment.
杰森:麦琪,你不要也太冲动了.
Jason: Maggie, don't you get irrational too.
麦琪:杰森,你就是太理智了,冲动点儿你会更好.
Maggie: Well Jason, it would be a nice gesture for you to get a little irrational.
杰森:如果你想发泄,继续,没人拦你,发泄,发泄好了.我们之中怎么也得有一个人保持冷静吧;怎么也得有一个人去思索,观察以及……
Jason: Ok, if you want to vent, go ahead and vent.Vent.One of us has to remain calm.One of us has to do thinking and observing and..
麦琪:你在说什么胡话呢?
Maggie: What are you babbling about?
杰森:我去打电话给他个臭小子,就现在.
Jason: I'm going to call that little slime bag sucker, right now.
(舞会当天夜晚)
(The Night of the Dance)
麦琪:开萝尔,宝贝,
Maggie: Carol honey, we want to leave in about five minutes.
我们五分钟后就出去了,你准备好了么?
Are you almost ready?
开萝尔:没.我不想去看什么无聊的比赛,
Carol: No, I am not.
会把我的心思岔开的.我一直在想今晚有那么一场舞会,
I do not want to go to some stupid play to take my mind off the
无聊透顶,我根本不会在乎的.
fact that there is some stupid dance tonight that I don't even care about.
杰森:再多给她一分钟就好了.
Jason: Six minutes will be fine.
麦琪:如果你想知道激情是什么样,告诉她我们去哪儿,
Maggie: If you're looking for enthusiasm,
可能会有帮助哦.
it might help to tell her where we are going.
杰森:不过,我觉得,
Jason: Well I don't think that we can expect much enthusiasm out of Carol
今晚上我们不可能指望开萝尔会有什么激情了.
tonight.
麦琪:我刚才说的是我的激情.本,
Maggie: I was talking about me.Ben, why are you eating?
为什么你在吃东西?我不是告诉你了么,我们要出去吃晚饭.
I told you we were going out to dinner.
本:不,我们不去.我们要去哪儿吃晚餐啊?
Ben: No we're not.Where we're going they don't have dinner.
杰森:嘘----!
Jason: Shhhh!
麦琪:我们10岁的儿子,你说我们今晚去哪儿吃饭,但是不要让我知道.
Maggie: You tell out ten year old son where we're going but you won't tell me.
本:别太在意,妈妈.女人守不住秘密的.
Ben: Don't take it personally mum.No woman can keep a secret.
杰森:哈!他会从哪儿得来这种荒唐的想法的呢?
Jason: Ha!Where would he get such a ridiculous idea?
本:不是从你那儿,爸爸.
Ben: Not from you dad.
麦琪:哦,哇,迈克.你看起来太帅了.
Maggie: Oh wow mike.You look fabulous.
迈克:什么太帅了,这件东西?
Mike: What, this old thing?
麦琪:我给你照张像.
Maggie: Let me get my camera.
杰森:那,你的女伴是谁啊?
Jason: So, who's the lucky date?
迈克:实际上呢,这是一个很艰难的抉择,爸爸.我给予了长时间的思考,不是我一般的长,我是说很长很长时间的思考.最后,也不怕您笑话,爸爸,为了这个我许多个夜晚都失眠了.如果说有什么合理的选择,那么只有一个.
Mike: Well it was a tough decision dad.I mean I have given this a lot of thought, and I mean a lot.And who's kidding who dad, I've lost a lot of sleep over this.There was only one decision that seemed to make any sense.
(门铃)
(door bell)
迈克:失陪了.
Mike: Excuse me.
三个女孩:你好,迈克.
Three girls: Hello Mike.
萨曼塔:你好,最近还好么?
Samantha: Hello, how do you do?
希娜:嗨!
Sheena: Hay!
迈克:妈妈,爸爸.
Mike: Mum dad.This is the stunning Samantha.
这是光彩夺目的萨曼塔;妩媚动人的安德里亚;还有风华绝代的希娜*布鲁克维茨.
Lovely Andrea, and the legendary Sheena Brookwitz.
麦琪:太漂亮了,你们整个这一群,啧啧.
Maggie: well you look lovely.The whole crowd of you.Cheese.
迈克:好了,妈妈,爸爸.那我们晚些时候再见.哦,还有啊,不用等我了.谁开车?
Mike: Ok mum, dad.We'll see you guys a little bit later.Oh and, there's no need to wait up.Who wants to drive?
安德里亚:我.
Andrea: Me.
萨曼塔:我到后座和迈克坐一起.
Samantha: I get to sit in the back with Mike.
希娜:是谁说的?
Sheen: Who says?
麦琪:说两句吧.
Maggie: Well, say something.
杰森:真是我的儿子.哦,看开萝尔.太漂亮了!
Jason: That's my boy.Oh look at Carol.Doesn't she look beautiful?
麦琪:哦,宝贝,
Maggie: Oh honey, you are perfectly dressed for a wonderful evening of...
你打扮得非常得体,是要去参加一晚精彩的……什么
Something or other.
开萝尔:我讨厌所有的这些低级,粗俗的想法.
Carol: I hate this whole entire gross disgusting idea.
杰森:今晚,你要过一个有生以来最愉快的一天,因为你已经满16岁了.来啊.
Jason: Tonight you re going to have more fun than I think you've had since you were six years old.Come on.
开萝尔:我要吐了.
Carol: I'm going to puke.
本:哇,这晚可要有好戏了.
Ben: Wow, this is going to be a fun night.
本:哦,上帝!请让它停一停.
Ben: Oh god!Please make it stop.
麦琪:没事的,本,起来.
Maggie: It's ok Ben.Get up.
开萝尔:我的我的.找到了."帝国大厦",
Carol: My my.Here it is.The Empire State Building.Spectacular.
纪念品,多好看啊.我们现在走么?
Oh souvenirs, what a view.Can we go now?
麦琪:杰森,快走了,时候不早了.
Maggie: Jason, it is very late.
杰森:胡说,夜晚永远年轻.(注:上文中it is very late双关)
Jason: Tish tosh, the night is young.
麦琪:胡说?那我们什么时候去看?
Maggie: Tish tosh?When are we getting to the surprise destination?
杰森:这个时候.
Jason: This is it.
麦琪:你在开玩笑?
Maggie: You're kidding?
本:不,他没有.很奇怪.
Ben: No he isn't.Surprise.
杰森:你不记得了么,你六岁那年,我们到这儿来,
Jason: Don't you remember when you were six years old we came over here
你看那个望远镜,然后说,"
and you looked through that very telescope and you said 'Daddy there must
爸爸,上面一定有魔法,连新泽西都看起来那么漂亮".
be magic up here.Even New Jersey looks pretty'.
开萝尔:爸爸,我的6岁已经一去不复返了.
Carol: Dad, I'm not six anymore.
杰森:不过,我在想或许你今晚还可以看到一些什么魔法呢,
Jason: I know, but I thought maybe you could use a bit of magic tonight
或许你老爸我可以帮一把.好了,谁想要这个纪念品?
and maybe your old dad could help out.Ok, who wants a King Kong souvenir?
本:我我我!
Ben: Me me me!
杰森:我是怎么知道的?
Jason: How did I know that?
麦琪:真的是很漂亮,看这些小汽车,
Maggie: Well, it really is beautiful up here.Look at all those little cars.
看起来像是……
They look like...
开萝尔:蚂蚁,我知道的,妈妈,请不要再说了.
Carol: Ants.I know mum.Please.
麦琪:开萝尔,你爸爸是好意.
Maggie: Carol, your father meant well.
开萝尔:我知道他是好意,
Carol: I know he did.
但是想到"帝国大厦"的魔法会麻醉我,让我忘记自己的奇耻大辱,
But thinking that the magic of the Empire State Building would make me
这样只会使爸爸看起来有点……
forget that I was totally humiliated, just makes dad seem kind of...
麦琪:很乏味?不,别让么说.
Maggie: Lame.No.
开萝尔:对,这是你说的.
Carol: Yes, I heard you.
麦琪:不不不,宝贝.
Maggie: No no no honey.
即使我真的那么想,我也绝对绝对绝对不会说你爸爸……
Even if I thought that I would never ever ever call your father...
开萝尔:乏味.
Carol: Lame.
麦琪:别再说了.
Maggie: Don't say it again.
开萝尔:好吧,但这的确是很乏味.
Carol: Ok, but it is lame.
麦琪:好,就算是.不过,我们从来没有进行过这样的交谈.
Maggie: Well, yes.But we never had this conversation.
开萝尔:什么交谈?
Carol: What conversation?
麦琪:为什么非得是你爸爸去跟那个踢足球的去谈?
Maggie: Why is your father talking to that janitor?
开萝尔:因为那是博比*维耐特.
Carol: Oh that's just Bobby Winette.
麦琪:哦.
Maggie: Oh.
开萝尔:博比*维耐特?
Carol: Bobby Winette?
麦琪:哦,上帝,原谅我说过关于杰森的话吧,千万别让他知道.
Maggie: Oh lord, forgive me for what I said about Jason and don't ever let him know.
开萝尔:妈妈,爸爸把他带到这儿了.
Carol: Mum, he's bringing him over here.
杰森:看,多可爱的傻瓜.看哪,我找到了谁?
Jason: Well what a coink ee dink.Look who I found.
博比:哦,嗨.
Bobby: Oh hi.
开萝尔:嗨.
Carol: Hi.
博比:你家老头,
Bobby: Your old man,
你父亲向我保证过说他不会告诉别人我在这儿上班的.
your father promised me he wouldn't tell nobody I was working here.
杰森:我谁也没告诉啊.
Jason: I didn't tell a soul.
麦琪:他告诉你那个了?
Maggie: He told you that?
博比:对,他电话里告诉我的.
Bobby: When he called me.
麦琪:你给他打过电话?
Maggie: You called him?
博比:对,扯着嗓子吼.
Bobby: Yeah, yelling.
开萝尔:问题是,你为什么不能带我去舞会?
Carol: This job is why you couldn't take me to the dance?
博比:我不带你去,还会有什么原因?
Bobby: Why else wouldn't I take you?
开萝尔:那我不知道.我想,可能会是……
Carol: Well I don't know.I thought maybe...
本:如果有人要在这里儿女情长的话,我要回避了.
Ben: If this is going to get mushy, I'm going to jump.
开萝尔:赶紧走吧,本.
Carol: Bye Ben.
博比:哦,希佛医生,如果可以的话,我可以开车送开萝尔回家么?在我11点下班之后.
Bobby: Oh Doctor Seaver, if it's ok, can I drive Carol home?I mean I get off work at eleven o'clock.
杰森:哦天,博比,我不知道……
Jason: Oh gee Bobby, I don't know...
开萝尔:爸爸!
Carol: Dad!
麦琪:别太晚了,宝贝.
Maggie: Don't be too late sweet heart.
开萝尔:我们不会的.
Carol: We won't.
麦琪:晚安,博比.
Maggie: Night Bobby.
开萝尔:谢谢你爸爸.
Carol: Thanks dad.
麦琪:哦,亲爱的.对不起,从来没想到你整个主意是如此的……
Maggie: Oh honey.I'm sorry I ever thought your whole idea was...
杰森:乏味?
Jason: Lame?
麦琪:哦,我可从来没那么想过.
Maggie: Oh I never thought that.
开萝尔:你为什么早告诉我你要工作呢?
Carol: Well why didn't you just tell me you had to work?
博比:我不想任何人知道博比*维耐特,作为足球队长,
Bobby: I didn't want anybody to know, that Bobby Winette,
还得做这样的工作.尤其是你.
captain of the football team, had a job doing this.Especially you.
开萝尔:我不会在意的.
Carol: Well I don't mind.
博比:很脏的.
Bobby: It's disgusting.
开萝尔:不要担心,脏东西我已经习惯了.忘了?我有两个兄弟的哦.
Carol: Don't worry.I'm used to disgusting.Remember I have two brothers.
博比:开萝尔,我真是想过带你去舞会.
Bobby: Carol, I really wanted to take you to that dance.
开萝尔:我真的是想过让我带我去舞会.
Carol: I really wanted to go with you.
博比:停!我知道,这也不会挑得太明.我可以请您跳个舞么?
Bobby: Wait here!I know this isn't going to be too clear.Can I have this dance?
开萝尔:当然可以.等会儿.好的,我现在准备好了.
Carol: Sure.Wait.Ok, I'm ready now.
女孩:过得真没劲.
Girl: I had a lousy time.
迈克:我也觉得没劲.谁要你们?你们哪一个会有人要?
Mike: Well I had a lousy time too.Who needs you?Any of you.
女孩的声音:你这只猪.
Girl's voice: You are a total pig.
迈克:我这辈子最倒霉的一天.女人.
博比:他说过的.
00:22:49,500
Mike: Was the worst night of my life.Women. Bobby: He said it.